<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Amir Sadoughi (mobile)</title><link>http://blog.princehonest.com/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 22:50:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Why mobile is broken for me</title><link>http://blog.princehonest.com/posts/why-mobile-is-broken-for-me.html</link><dc:creator>Amir Sadoughi</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I walk around with me three things on my person: a wallet, a smartphone,
and a set of keys. Why can't these three things all be the same device? In
addition, I pay to carry a mobile hotspot around as a separate device sometimes.
Why can't I use my phone as a mobile hotspot regularly with real unlimited data?
The former problem is an innovation problem. The latter is a service problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="a-virtual-keyring"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Virtual Keyring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, by now, you have heard of Lockitron, August, or similar technologies
built around the home keyhole. Last time I checked, I have more keys on my
keyring than just my apartment key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a car key and a postbox key. For the car, companies like Viper have
come up with an app that can lock and unlock your car over a cellular network.
This does not seem like the future I want. How hard would it be to emulate a
key fob radio physically in a phone? Could phones have software-defined radios?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, with the postbox key, granted, I live in an apartment so most
homeowners probably don't have a postbox key. I could also do without physical
mail if I signed up for a service like Outbox, but that comes with its own set
of problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A keyring should be an app on my phone, that's all I am saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="a-mobile-wallet"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Mobile Wallet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, for the wallet, I carry membership cards, gift cards, debit/credit cards,
ID cards, and sometimes cash. Credit cards are already being eaten away by the
likes of ISIS and Square. Insurance cards and membership cards I probably could
store as photos assuming the vendor allows me to type in the ID number. Some
member cards, like Starbucks, are already pure digital apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest obstacle that I'm not aware of being solved any time soon is the
digitalization of ID cards. Effectively, the government would have to rely on a
certain level of security and ubiquity to allow for digital IDs. While it might
introduce new problems, the problem of fake IDs as it exists now could be
eradicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mobile-internet-service"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mobile Internet Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now I have my wallet and keyring in my phone, what's next? Well, how about
Internet service? Do you have a landline or wireless service? I currently carry
wireless service through Clear. Clear operates over Sprint's networks. So, why
can't I have my phone operate as an unlimited data mobile hotspot on Sprint if
I can already do that by carrying around an extra hotspot? It doesn't make sense
to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all small, solvable modern problems. A decade from now I look forward
to this technology becoming obsolete. We'll see where we're headed next then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>future</category><category>mobile</category><guid>http://blog.princehonest.com/posts/why-mobile-is-broken-for-me.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 05:08:18 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>